Duran Humes

Full Stack Software Engineer with a focus on frontend

In my 3 year career so far I've worked on numerous products for charitable organizations, governments, fortune 500 companies and startups with a lot of happy clients and team mates.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Full Time

Codelitt -> Feb 2019 - Aug 2019 -> Remote

• Built user stories to client specifications.

- Refactored major parts of our largest client's React & Node.js codebase which lead to easier, more consistent, and less error prone code/feature updates.
- Reviewed potential software developer hires.

Software Engineer - Contract

PeepX -> Sept 2018 - Dec 2018 -> Remote

- Led development of the PeepX mobile app and had an MVP in just under 2 months after I
 joined, which led to the app getting grant funding from Princeton University.
- Mentored 6 software developers with things like general programming and research to more nuanced things like systems design/architecture to help them become better software developers.
- Built in-house maps, geolocation, and search engine services to cut costs for the company.

Software Engineer - Full Time

Bahamaslocal -> Dec 2017 - Feb 2019 -> The Bahamas

- Used Elasticsearch, Node.js, & PHP to lead the development of a new search engine and REST API for Bahamaslocal's website and mobile app.
- Led development of an in-house maps service as a replacement for Google maps with Node.js & OSM. It's used by clients and Bahamaslocal's main site and has in total over 1m hits per month. I learned a lot about scaling a service to handle loads while working on this.
- Built an inventory management web app with PHP for a local charity. The web app got some
 publicity in the press which led to the company getting more contracts for work.
 https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=10155526152408364

Phone: +1 (242) 812-2195

Email: duranhumes@gmail.com

Blog: medium.com/@codeduran

Website: duranhumes.com

Github: github.com/duranhumes

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/duranhumes

SKILLS

JavaScript

React

Node.js

React-Native

MySQL

MongoDB

Git

PHP

SELECTED PROJECTS

Portfolio

RemindMe

Github Search

EDUCATION

Bahamas Technical Vocational Institute

Associates Degree - I.T. Management +Networking

MISCELLANEOUS

Creator of a local monthly tech event for developers where we collaborate on different projects.

Interests: gym, comedy, music, real estate, swimming.